Naga Jyothi Patchigolla

Fremont, CA

E-mail: jyothi.knj@gmail.com

Mobile: +1-669 210 2114

OBJECTIVE: 6 years of experience in Siebel CRM development as Staff Consultant and Team lead.

To obtain an excellent career in the industry and be in a good position in a developing organization, which gives me an opportunity to show the best of my ability with all my skills practically with hard work and dedication.

CERTIFICATIONS:

- Oracle Siebel 8.0 Consultant Certified Expert
- Siebel 7.7 Certified Consultant
- Siebel 7.7 Certified Integration Consultant

EXPERIENCE:

Staff Consultant, Oracle Solution Services India Ltd, Oct 2007 - Nov 2010 Software Engineer, IBM Global Services India Ltd, Sep 2004 - Sep 2007

TECHNICAL SKILLS:

- ❖ Programming Languages: Python, C, C++, Java, COBOL, VB
- **Python for Data Science:** Panda, Numpy and MatplotLib packages.
- ❖ Finance: Financial and Management Accounting, Corporate Finance, Valuation and Investment Analysis.
- CRM: Siebel Configuration, eScripting, Workflow Processes, Configuration, EAI, Web Services, Outbound and Inbound Email configurations, CTI, Runtime Events, Business Rule Processor and Data Validation Manager.
- ❖ Database skills: Oracle 8, PL/SQL

EDUCATION / TECHNICAL BACKGROUND

Degree/ Examination	Name of The Institution	Year of Passing	Aggregate
General Management Program for IT Executives	Indian Institute of Management, Bangalore (IIMB)	2012	A
Bachelors of Technology (B.Tech.) in Computer Science and Engineering	JNTU College of Engineering, Kakinada	2004	77.52

ACHIEVEMENTS/ ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Received **IBM Bravo Award** for Contribution to the Unilever Project in 2006.
- Received **PRATHIBHA** Award from **Chief Minister of Andhra Pradesh,India** in the year 2000 for the outstanding performance in Intermediate College (12th Grade equivalent).

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Project: MTN

Client: MTN South Africa

Application Version: Siebel Loyalty 8.1.1

Duration: Sep 2008-Nov 2010. Team Size: 5

Role: Team Lead

• Led the team for the deployment of interfaces in the Loyalty Management track.

• Prepared the functional design documents and played a critical role in technical design, development and deployment of all the integration flows in the Loyalty.

Project: Shire

Client: Shire Pharmaceutical Company, UK

Application Version: Siebel 8.0 Duration: Feb 2008 to August 2008.

Team Size: 6

Role: Part of Technical Design and Development

- Designed and implemented the modules Calendar, Meetings, Customer Calls, Samples and Lots in Siebel 8.0 Pharma vertical.
- Responsible for importing all the Symbolic String translations in the multilingual implementation for different languages using Locale Management Utility.

Project: Siebel 8.0 Content Preparation

Client: Oracle Romania

Application Version: Siebel 8.0 Duration: Oct 2007 to Jan 2008.

Role: Team Lead

• Co-ordinated the team for preparing the Siebel 8.0 content presentations and lab exercises.

Team Size: 5

- Reviewed and evaluated the lab exercises and module presentations before submitting for the client approval.
- Involved in preparation of the presentations for Siebel State Model, Assignment Manager and Workflows.

Project: RaboBank

Client: RaboBank Netherlands Application Version: Siebel 7.8

Duration: Jan 2007 to Sep 2007. Team Size: 25

Role: Part of Technical Design and Development

- Worked on Business Rule Processor, Workflows and Runtime Events for the automation of validation and verification of the Contact records. Also worked in the area of Visibility of the Product Catalogue and Asset Management.
- Worked with the Symbolic URLs that call an external application.
- Involved in the Merge and Sync Process of previous Release (R3.0) in current Release (R3.1).

Project: Unilever Acumen

Client: Unilever Role: Developer

Application Version: Siebel 7.7

Duration: April 2005 – Dec 2006.

Team Size: 30

Role: Technical Developer

- Responsible for analyzing the requirements, designing, coding and unit testing.
- Part of the Malaysia R3.5 Development team. Have taken up the responsibility of technical design and development of Customer Reimbursement module entirely. Played a major role in setting up data for the release.
- Part of the Performance Team that deals with the performance in configuration and scripting areas of the application developed and tried to minimize the response time.
- Received the "IBM Bravo Award" for Contribution to the Unilever Project.
- Part of the Technical Design and Development team for the China release R3.5B and traveled to Shanghai, China for the support. Received Client appreciation.

Project: MCI

Client: MCI

Application Version: Siebel 7.5 and Siebel 7.7

Duration: Dec 2004 - Feb 2005 Team Size: 6

Role: Developer

- Worked as a UI Configurator.
- Created applets and views for the screens Accounts, Contacts, Quotes and Orders.